I've been using the iron bull wrist
straps for about a month now and my
three favorite things about them are the
multi-function Loop the cotton and
elastic build and the fact that you're
going to save money over the course of a
year as opposed to buying tape multiple
times if you're looking for a new way to
support your wrist while working out
might have just found your answer let's
get to this
[Music]
review
what's up y'all it's Jake back in the
barbing garage gy and for today's video
we're going to be talking about some
support gear with the iron bll unleash
wrist wraps all right so in this video
today we're going to talk about a lot
but specifically we're going to talk
about some money some pros and cons I've
experienced with these wraps and then of
course who should or maybe should not
make this purchase now pump the brakes
before I do that got to let y'all know
these are not the only wrist straps
we've reviewed we actually have a full
best list so if you want to check that
out all you got to do is search barbin
best wrist straps it's going to pull
right up for you you can find out for
yourself which ones that we like the
[Music]
best okay so before I start talking
about what I like about these wraps I
just want to take a second and explain
what a wrist wrap is for anybody who
doesn't know okay so wrist wraps are
very different from lift ing straps okay
so a lifting strap is designed to go
around a dumbbell a barbell a pull-up
bar really whatever it is and basically
it's going to take your grip strength
out of the equation so you're not being
limited and you're able to just focus on
the actual lift and work your muscles
more while a wrist wrap is designed to
go around your wrist and support that
joint and you know that really comes in
handy if you're somebody like me who has
a previous injury in your wrist or
really whenever you start lifting some
heavy weight that's basically it all
right so let's talk about what I like as
I mentioned earlier I really like the
actual build right here so I really like
how it's cotton and elastic you know
that cotton is you know going to feel
soft on your skin and comfortable but
that elastic really allows you to
stretch it and Achieve you know a really
tight fit and you know because of you
that I want to piggyback off of that I
really like how you know you're able to
customize that fit so I used to be you
know really big into wrist tape that was
just kind of my thing obviously that
gets expensive over time you know these
don't 35 bucks that's a really solid
deal but it's hard to you know mess with
the tightness of wrist tape you kind of
have to start from scratch again if you
mess up and that's something you don't
have to worry about you know with wrist
straps in general and that's a really
nice thing I also really enjoy the
multi-function Loop I'll show you guys
how to do that but you can wear these
wraps in two different ways and I think
that's a really cool thing right there
and then also these are just really high
quality and I don't see how they
wouldn't last you at least a year which
is also a great thing now as far as you
know actual cons go I can't really think
of you know anything negative about this
product the only thing that some people
may not like it really just boils down
to personal preference and you know
you're kind of lifting all right so if
you're a dedicated powerlifter and you
don't you're doing a lot of heavy bench
presses and you don't want that wrist to
bend back at all well then these might
not be perfect for you you might want to
go after you know a stiff wrist wrap
that way that wrist is basic basically
just staying in line the whole
[Music]
time all right so the iron bull unleash
wrist wraps you're going to run you
right around 35 bucks I think that's a
fair price tag they're really high
quality as I mentioned they're going to
last you a year at least I would say and
then you know rist tape already talked
about that wrist tape you know it's
going to cost you more than that
probably over the course of a year
especially if if you're messing up and
having to restart and you know all of
that but also you know the benefit one
of the main benefits about a wrist wrap
is that you're not being wasteful you
know with wrist tape you get one usage
out of it ball it up throw it in the
trash you're done you know so if you're
trying to avoid being wasteful this is
really solid now if you want to save you
know 15 bucks they also have their
classic wrist wraps they're $20 and
that's pretty much you know the market
Standard with you know those CL classic
wrist straps basically the main
difference there is the thumb Loop so
the thumb Loop kind of whenever it's you
know baled up like this rolled up that
thumb Loop you know sticks straight up
in the air and that's just a different
design so it kind of just depends but
honestly 35 bucks y'all you can't go
wrong okay so remember you have a cotton
and elastic build right here so yeah yes
it's high quality but it's also it's
going to feel you know pretty
comfortable on your skin and it's really
going to allow you to stretch it and
make it as tight as you want so got your
velcro right here your little velcro
strap these are 24 in long so you know
that allows you to once again you know
really get that perfect fit that you're
looking for and this is a 3in wide
profile so you know it's going to come
down your wrist a little bit right here
some people may not be too crazy about
that I think it's fine but you know
there's plenty of people who want to
Target you know a thinner wrist wrap so
definitely you just keep that in mind
now it comes in black as we have right
here also red and milspec green so it's
nice that there's some variation you
know if you're super into having your
you know workout gear all match and
everything you can you hopefully you
know find one that matches now this is
this this multi-function loop I was
talking about this is pretty unique it's
you know kind of hidden within the
actual strap which is nice and it's
probably going to help with durability
and everything like that but the main
reason for this is there's two different
ways for you to put this wrist wrap on
okay so this is kind of the classic way
you know with a loop where you just kind
of put it like that stretch it wrap it
around make sure it's comfortable you
know sometimes that can kind of raise up
on your hand a little bit and then here
you go now I like having it up here
there's a little bone right here called
your owner styloid that's where I want
that extra support and this is really
allows you to do that and as you can see
there's still some wrist you know
flexion right here so you want to do
those cleans and anything like that
you're really able to do that now the
other way this is really unique so
basically the best thing to do is go
ahead and start running the velcro
through it a little bit right there kind
of get it
started get it over that part all right
cool now you put your wrist in you just
kind of tighten it like that and then
you're able to really wrap it around
sometimes it will kind of twist on you a
little bit until you get it at like
perfect you know tightness right there
and then you're able to wrap it
around and really lock it into place and
this is where you know you really do
have you know a lot of wrist Mobility
right there so it's kind of you know I
guess appeasing to you know both ends of
the spectrum whether you want that wrist
to stay nice and neutral or you want a
little bit more flexion now these are
going to have more you know more flexion
than a stiff wrap so definitely don't
get it twisted if you're somebody who
doesn't doesn't want your wrist to move
at all this might not be the best for
you but being able to you know customize
your own fit is a really cool thing so
let's take the obvious here I think
these wrist wraps are ideal for anybody
who wants extra rist support in general
but you know they're also a really nice
alternative as opposed to buying wrist
tape multiple times a year and then
obviously only getting you know limited
usage out of that tape also you know if
you're a competitor I think you're going
to absolutely love the fact that these
are certified by all these federations
right here here now on the flip side
only reason I think somebody wouldn't
want to purchase these is if a you want
a thinner profile than this 3 in right
here and then B you know if you're just
looking for a stiffer wrist
[Music]
wrap all right well that's a wrap on
today's review over the iron bull
unleash wrist wraps these are affordable
they're really high quality and they're
certified by multiple federations thanks
for watching y'all I hope this video was
really helpful and that I was able to
tell you everything you need to know
about these rist straps as always stay
posted for my next video but for now
head over to barb. comom cuz we have a
full written article about these wrist
straps that you will probably find to be
really helpful so all you got to do is
search barbend Iron bull wrist wraps
review it's going to pull right up for
you you can go over every single thing
we talked about here today I'll catch
youall next
time
[Music]
he